LEARNING SITE PRIVACY POLICY
============================

**Last updated**: February 13, 2024 

This Learning Site Privacy Policy (“Policy”) describes the types of personal information (“PI”) that Wayside Publishing (“Company,” “we” or “our”) may collect or receive from you or about you when you visit or use the Learning Site website and Software-as-a-Service application accessible at [https://learningsite.waysidepublishing.com](https://learningsite.waysidepublishing.com/) (the “Service”), and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing that information. 

By visiting, accessing, or using or downloading content from the Service, you agree to our collection and use of personal information as this Policy describes. This Policy may change from time to time. Your continued use of the Service after any modification means that you acknowledge the change and agree to the practices that we disclose in the Policy. 

This Policy applies to the Service only. This Policy does not apply to
----------------------------------------------------------------------

* the Wayside Publishing corporate website, [www.waysidepublishing.com](http://www.waysidepublishing.com/); 
    
* third-party platforms and products with which we partner from time to time; or 
    
* personal information that we collect or receive offline or through any other means, including on any other website operated by Wayside Publishing or any third party (including our affiliates and subsidiaries). 

Relationship Between this Policy and Other Agreements, Policies and Disclosures 
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

If you use the Service in connection with a school or school district that is a customer of Wayside Publishing (a “Customer”), then written agreements between Wayside Publishing and you and/or that Customer may conflict with this Policy. For example, a written agreement between Wayside Publishing and either you or the Customer may provide you with rights not described in this Policy. 

We also maintain and publish other written policies, notices and disclosures about privacy and data protection (“Supplemental Policies”) that may apply to you as well. 

To the extent that any written agreement or written policy, notice or disclosure about privacy or data protection conflicts with any provision of this Policy, the provision that provides you the more favorable rights will apply to you. 

PI That You Manually Provide Us 
--------------------------------

The PI that you manually provide us through or in connection with the Service may include: 

* Information that you enter into forms on the Service. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use the Service, posting material to the Service, or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information if you report a problem with the Service. 
    
* Records and copies of your correspondence (including email addresses), if you contact us. 
    
* Your responses to surveys that we might ask you to complete for research purposes. 
    
* Where applicable, details of transactions that you carry out through the Service and of the fulfillment of your orders. 
    
* Search queries that you type into the Service’s search interface. 
    
* You also may provide information to be published or displayed (“posted”) on public areas of the Service or transmitted to other users of the Service or third parties (“User Contributions”). You post User Contributions and transmit them to others at your own risk. We cannot control the actions of other users of the Service with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions, so we cannot and do not guarantee that unauthorized people will not view your User Contributions. 

In these ways, you may provide us with PI that includes your answers to activities and tasks in Learning Site; audio and video recordings associated with activities, tasks and forums; your contact information (including your city, state, ZIP code and phone numbers(s) and email address(es)); your real name and username; your proficiency self-assessment results; your profile photograph(s); your password(s); your rostering or integration ID number; your SIS ID number; your responses to surveys; and information about how you have used the Service. 

PI That We Collect Automatically Through Data Collection Technologies 
----------------------------------------------------------------------

As you use the Service, we may use automatic data collection technologies to collect information about your equipment and browsing actions. These may include: 

* Details of your visits to the Service, including traffic data, location data, logs, and the resources that you access and use on the Service. 
    
* Information about your computer/device and Internet connection, including your IP address, operating system, and browser type. 

We collect this information to help us understand how people use the Service, how we can improve its speed, how we can make it easier for people to use. You may opt out of our use of some of these tools with respect to you. You can learn more about how to do so at the Digital Advertising Alliance’s [Webchoices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) page, European Advertising Standards Alliance (EASA)’s [Framework](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) and the [Network Advertising Initiative’s Consumer Opt Out](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/) page. 

How We Use Your PI
------------------

We use your PI to: 

* to provide the Service to you. 
    
* to provide you with information, products, or services that you request from us. 
    
* to let you know about changes to the Service or services we offer or provide through the Service. 
    
* to fulfill any other purpose for which you provide data. 
    
* to carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts that you enter into with us, including for billing and collection. 
    
* as otherwise described and disclosed in other written agreements that we are party to with you or with any Customer with which you are associated. 
    
* as otherwise described and disclosed in other written policies, notices, and disclosures that we publish relating to privacy and data protection. 

If we use your email address to communicate with you (with the exception of transactional emails regarding your use of the Service), we will provide you with the option to unsubscribe or opt out of future emails. 

How We Disclose PI to Third Parties 
------------------------------------

We may disclose aggregated information about our users, and information that does not identify any individual, without restriction or notification. 

We will not sell, rent, license or disclose PI to third parties except: 

* to work with third-party companies that we use to provide the Service or other products that we offer (“Third-Party Services,” below). 
    
* to third parties with which we partner or collaborate to provide material within our own products. 
    
* where we believe it is necessary to respond to legal claims asserted against us, to comply with legal process (e.g., warrants and/or subpoenas), to enforce or administer our agreements, to prevent fraud, for risk assessment, for investigation, and to protect the rights, property or safety of us, our users or others. 
    
* to investigate suspected fraud, harassment or illegal conduct, or suspected violations of our written agreements with Customers and individual users of our products and services. 

* to subsidiaries or affiliates that we may have in the future. 
    
* to a buyer or other successor in the case of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of Wayside Publishing’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which the transferred assets include PI held by Wayside Publishing about you. 
    
* as otherwise described and disclosed in other written agreements that we are party to with you or with any Customer with which you are associated. 
    
* as otherwise described and disclosed in other written policies, notices, and disclosures that we publish relating to privacy and data protection. 
    
* to fulfill the purpose for which you provide data. 

Third-Party Services
--------------------

We use various Third-Party Services to operate the Service. These include [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics) and other Google products and may include others in the future. 

Third-Party Services collect, use, and share PI pursuant to their own privacy and security policies. Some of them, including Google, may use location information to serve advertisements to consumers (not students) on their respective websites. By using our Service, you consent to our providing PI with Third-Party Services to be used in accordance with their own privacy and security policies as they exist today and as they may change in the future. 

For more information about how Google’s services use PI, see “[How Google uses information from sites](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) [or apps that use our services.”](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) 

DATA SECURITY; WAIVER OF CLAIMS 
--------------------------------

EXCEPT AS WE MAY EXPRESSLY STATE OTHERWISE IN THIS POLICY OR EXPRESSLY AGREE WITH YOU IN AN AGREEMENT SEPARATE FROM THIS POLICY, WE CANNOT AND DO NOT WARRANT OR PROMISE THAT YOUR PI WILL BE FREE FROM UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS BY THIRD PARTIES WHEN YOU USE THE SERVICE. BY USING THE SERVICE, YOU 

(A) CONSENT TO OUR USING YOUR PI AS DESCRIBED IN THIS POLICY DESPITE THIS RISK; 

2. (B) WAIVE ANY CLAIMS AGAINST US OR ANY PARENT, SUBSIDIARY OR AFFILIATE COMPANY THAT WE HAVE OR MAY HAVE IN THE FUTURE RELATING TO THE INTERCEPTION, USE OR DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PI BY THIRD PARTIES UNAUTHORIZED BY US; AND (C) AGREE TO NOTIFY US PROMPTLY IF YOU SUSPECT ANY UNAUTHORIZED USAGE OF PI. 

For Children Under the Age of Thirteen
--------------------------------------

Students under the age of thirteen (13) who access our Learning Site platform are subject to the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) and other applicable law. Wayside Publishing collects personal information for the use and benefit of Schools and/or School Districts, and for education purposes authorized by the contracting school and/or school district. When a school or school district provides access to the Wayside Publishing Learning Site, the school or school district provides that the school or school district has obtained the necessary consent from parents of children under the age of thirteen (13) or is providing consent on parents’ behalf. If you are the parent of a student who uses the Learning Site platform through his/her/their School and have questions regarding our Learning Site privacy practices, please contact your respective School and/or School District.  

Your Rights With Respect to PI 
-------------------------------

You may update certain types of PI that we keep about you by using the tools provided in the Service’s interface to manually update that PI. Not all users of the Service have these tools provided to them, however, so if the Service does not provide you with those tools and you are using the Service in connection with a school or school district that is a customer of Wayside Publishing, you may ask that school or school district to update your PI in the Service and we will comply with any such request that your associated school or school district makes to us in writing. We will also comply with any written request that we may receive from your associated school or school district customer to delete PI that we maintain about you. 

“Do Not Track” Technology
-------------------------

If you use Do-Not-Track tools to prevent websites and software products from tracking your online behavior across websites, please be aware that we do not change the way the Service works (as described in this Policy) in response to requests not to be tracked. You may, however, be able to disable certain tracking signals used by individual Third-Party Services, which you may do by accessing those services. 

No Rights of Third Parties 
---------------------------

This Policy does not create rights enforceable by third parties, nor does it require disclosure of any information relating to users of the Service. 

Limitation of Warranties
------------------------

We make no representations, warranties, or promises about the security of PI except as stated expressly in this Policy or where required by law. 

ADDITIONAL RIGHTS IN SPECIFIC JURISDICTIONS
-------------------------------------------

For customers residing in California, Illinois, Kansas, and Virginia, state law grants you additional rights under applicable law (see below for information on the rights granted for each state and when those are effective). You, or your legal representative may submit a request to exercise your rights by contacting [Legal@waysidepublishing.com.](mailto:legal@waysidepublishing.com) 

For Our Customers Residing in California 
-----------------------------------------

California law requires that we provide certain disclosures, including a description of legal rights, to those who reside in the state of California. If you are a California resident and a Wayside Publishing customer, this section applies in addition to all other applicable rights and information contained in this Policy. 

Your Rights as a California Resident 
-------------------------------------

As a California resident, you have the right to request: 

* To know more about and access your personal information. 
    
* That we correct your personal information that is inaccurate. 
    
* That we delete your personal information. 
    
* To opt-out of the sale or sharing of your personal information In addition to the rights above, California consumers have: 
    
* The right to limit the use and disclosure of sensitive personal information collected about them 
    
* The right to non-discrimination for exercising their CCPA rights 

In addition to these rights, California law also provides you the right to request that we limit the use of 

your “sensitive” personal information. Wayside Publishing does not use any sensitive personal information to make inferences about you and uses sensitive personal information only for reasons permitted by the California Consumer Privacy Act. 

Do Not Sell My Personal Information 
------------------------------------

Wayside Publishing does not work with advertising partners to show ads that are targeted to your interests. Such activities may be considered “selling” or “sharing” of your personal information under the California Privacy Rights Act (“CPRA”). Please note that we may continue to collect and share personal information about you with other third parties, including to continue providing services to you where sharing of your personal information is for purposes other than targeted advertising and permitted by law. To opt out of our selling of your personal information, as the CPRA defines “selling” and “sale,” you may: email us that request at [Privacy@WaysidePublishing.com.](mailto:Privacy@WaysidePublishing.com) 

The rights granted to you under California law may provide us with exceptions to fulfilling your request, including where we need to retain the information to fulfill a legal obligation, complete a transaction with you, prevent fraud or any other purpose permitted by law. 

For Customers Residing in Virginia 
-----------------------------------

Virginia law requires that we provide certain disclosures, including a description of legal rights, to those who reside in the state of Virginia. If you are a Virginia resident and a Wayside Publishing customer, this section applies in addition to all other applicable rights and information contained in this Policy. 

Your Rights as a Virginia Resident 
-----------------------------------

As a Virginia resident, you have the right to request: 

* To know more about and access your personal information. 
    
* That we correct your personal information that is inaccurate. 
    
* That we delete your personal information. 
    
* To opt out of the processing of your personal information for the purposes of providing you with targeted advertising. 

Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information 
---------------------------------------------

Wayside Publishing does not work with advertising partners to show ads that are targeted to your interests. Such activities may be considered “selling” or “sharing” of your personal information under California law. Please note that we may continue to collect and share personal information about you with other third parties, including to continue providing services to you where sharing of your personal information is for purposes other than targeted advertising and permitted by law. To opt out of our selling of your personal information: email us that request at [Privacy@WaysidePublishing.com.](mailto:Privacy@WaysidePublishing.com) 

The rights granted to you under Virginia law may provide us with exceptions to fulfilling your request, including where we need to retain the information to fulfill a legal obligation, complete a transaction with you, prevent fraud or any other purpose permitted by law. 

For Customers Residing in Illinois and Kansas 
----------------------------------------------

Wayside Publishing complies with the Student Online Personal Protection Act (“SOPPA”). Wayside Publishing ensures that student data will be protected when collect for use with the Wayside Publishing Learning Site. Data is used for beneficial purposes such as providing personalized learning and innovative learning technology. Wayside publishing does not engage in targeted advertising to students. Schools and/or School Districts within the State of Illinois are encouraged to submit a SOPPA agreement when contracting with Wayside Publishing.  

Contact us 
-----------

If you have questions about the Policy or our privacy practices, please contact us at: 

Wayside Publishing 

2 Stonewood Drive 

Freeport, Maine 04032  

888-302-2519 (Live phone support is available Monday through Friday from 8:30 a.m. – 4:30 p.m. EST) 

Copyright © 2010 - 2024

Wayside Publishing. All rights reserved.
